<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="2.5.3">Jekyll</generator>
<link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
<link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
<updated>2015-12-27T13:42:39-05:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<entry>
<title>Elizabeth Weil / Andreesen Horowitz</title>
<link href="/ElizabethWeil/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elizabeth Weil / Andreesen Horowitz" />
<published>2015-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
<updated>2015-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
<id>/ElizabethWeil</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="/ElizabethWeil/">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How does a design perspective help in evaluating an investment decision, in obvious ways?&lt;/b&gt; I have found companies that have some eye toward design can tell their story better. A visually pleasing presentation slide deck even seems to give entrepreneurs more confidence as they tell their story in that initial pitch meeting. Clearly and crisply getting the message across in an initial presentation can kick-start the conversation and provide hooks to doing further work considering the investment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How does a design perspective help in evaluating an investment decision, in non-obvious ways?&lt;/b&gt; I have also found that when I&amp;#39;m listening to entrepreneurs pitch, and considering an investment, a solid design perspective provides clues about what future work with this team may be like. Will they communicate data in effective ways? What will board meetings be like? How do they prioritize? Also, design is so much how the product &amp;quot;feels.&amp;quot; If they can convey this to users, there is likelihood for more success.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Where have you seen a designer&amp;#39;s perspective possibly harmful in the investment process?&lt;/b&gt; I&amp;#39;ve seen design is too much of a focus to the point of hindering progress, iteration, and in turn just making the company operationally slow. Some small teams can over-rotate on design focus, and then forget about some of the important engineering or business perspectives too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are three characteristics in a company&amp;#39;s structure/history that will likely lead to success in leveraging design?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a design-minded founder or a founding team that really appreciates the value of good design is a great sign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having design in the top of the org chart as the company grows can help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having design in place from the beginning is a great indicator that it will continue to be an important part of the company&amp;#39;s DNA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How do you best support CEOs with a purely technical and/or business background to leverage design in their startup?&lt;/b&gt; Make a great hire at the beginning. Pay them well, give them a seat and a voice at the table, and empower him/her to act like a founder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are a few challenges you&amp;#39;ve seen in working with companies that have caught &amp;quot;the design bug&amp;quot; -- especially the CEO?&lt;/b&gt; Some companies with this can over-rotate on emphasis on design. This can create slower decision-making and iteration cadence, excuses on lack of progress, and the potential to ignore some of the other early important factors like business model and engineering roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
<summary>How does a design perspective help in evaluating an investment decision, in obvious ways? I have found companies that have some eye toward design can tell their story better. A visually pleasing presentation slide deck even seems to give entrepreneurs more confidence as they tell their story in that initial pitch meeting. Clearly and crisply getting the message across in an initial presentation can kick-start the conversation and provide hooks to doing further work considering the investment.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Irene Au / Khosla Ventures</title>
<link href="/IreneAu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Irene Au / Khosla Ventures" />
<published>2015-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</published>
<updated>2015-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
<id>/IreneAu</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="/IreneAu/">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How does a design perspective help in evaluating an investment decision, in obvious ways?&lt;/b&gt; Designers are highly tuned in to user needs and natural human behaviors, since this is deeply linked to what they do as designers.  Their insights inform whether an offering truly addresses a human need, and whether the proposed solution has the potential to successfully address those needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How does a design perspective help in evaluating an investment decision, in non-obvious ways?&lt;/b&gt; Design is a manifestation of what a company values, the principles that guide their decisions, and its ability to execute.  Bad design is a reflection of some internal failure within the company.  Read my post &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/swlh/ux-is-a-canary-in-a-coal-mine-b7764b77f371#.q4os04eil&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Where have you seen a designer&amp;#39;s perspective possibly harmful in the investment process?&lt;/b&gt; Just because a company’s offering is not aesthetically pleasing does not mean that it is not a potential investment hit.  Also, an overinvestment in design can sometimes lead to navel-gazing and too much focus on issues that are not really the core problem to solve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are three characteristics in a company&amp;#39;s structure/history that will likely lead to success in leveraging design?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear vision and mission, sense of purpose, raison d’etre&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A strong point of view that guides key decisions for product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decisive leadership to support #1 and 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How do you best support CEOs with a purely technical and/or business background to leverage design in their startup?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help them recruit a great design leader / designer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point out potential pitfalls with their product if they do not get the design right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get them close to users to gain insight into their needs and how to best address their needs with their offering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are a few challenges you&amp;#39;ve seen in working with companies that have caught &amp;quot;the design bug&amp;quot; -- especially the CEO?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Naive understanding of what design is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talks the talk but doesn’t commit to making design a priority (failure to bring in great talent, failure to empower design, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
<summary>How does a design perspective help in evaluating an investment decision, in obvious ways? Designers are highly tuned in to user needs and natural human behaviors, since this is deeply linked to what they do as designers.  Their insights inform whether an offering truly addresses a human need, and whether the proposed solution has the potential to successfully address those needs.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Jake Knapp&amp;rsquo;s New Book / Google Ventures</title>
<link href="/JakeKnapp-Sprint/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jake Knapp&amp;rsquo;s New Book / Google Ventures" />
<published>2015-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
<updated>2015-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
<id>/JakeKnapp-Sprint</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="/JakeKnapp-Sprint/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jakek/status/677248434282340352&quot;&gt;Jake Knapp&lt;/a&gt;, John Zeratsky, and Braden Kowitz have a new book coming out entitled &amp;quot;SPRINT&amp;quot; that is now available for &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1RSJiOI&quot;&gt;pre-order&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sprintbooknew.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SPRINT: The Book&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>Jake Knapp, John Zeratsky, and Braden Kowitz have a new book coming out entitled &amp;quot;SPRINT&amp;quot; that is now available for pre-order.  </summary>
</entry>
</feed>
